<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on koslib</title>
    <link>https://www.koslib.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on koslib</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.koslib.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting with EKS Fargate profiles and AWS LB Controller</title>
      <link>https://www.koslib.com/posts/eks-fargate-aws-lb-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koslib.com/posts/eks-fargate-aws-lb-controller/</guid>
      <description>Intro With more and more apps running on Kubernetes, EKS is definitely one of the best managed-Kubernetes options in the market. I have been using EKS in production applications for the last year or so. Up until recently, most deployments on EKS were made using an NLB (Network Load Balancer), as creating an ALB (Application Load Balancer) for every service is at least cost-wise suboptimal.
The latest version of AWS Load Balancer Controller, an ingress controller by AWS, was published a few weeks ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy apps on Kubernetes with GitHub Actions - from start to finish</title>
      <link>https://www.koslib.com/posts/deploy-k8s-apps-helm-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koslib.com/posts/deploy-k8s-apps-helm-complete/</guid>
      <description>After many years of using DroneCI, Gitlab or Travis for most of my projects, I thought to give Github Actions (GA) a try. My scope was to deploy a side-project I have on AWS EKS, but make it as automated as possible in every aspect.
Then I quickly realized that no good complete tutorials, or at least people talking about their experience on this exact matter existed, and decided to write up my own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simplistic explanation of the entity services anti-pattern</title>
      <link>https://www.koslib.com/posts/entity-services-anti-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koslib.com/posts/entity-services-anti-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been participating in discussions where microservices patterns are the hottest topic.
People coming from Java background most of the time go for a software design comprised of entity services. Spring even has a tutorial about creating entity services. Microsoft does too. That nearly explains why, I presume.
In this post, I will explain my view on this anti-pattern.
Backgound Once upon a time, there was a huge monolith. It started as a great initiative and helped the dev team release features easily and, frankly, quite fast especially in the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You need to be this tall to do micro-services</title>
      <link>https://www.koslib.com/posts/microservices-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koslib.com/posts/microservices-101/</guid>
      <description>Hello, is this thing on?
Alright, now that we&amp;rsquo;ve established that this is a place where I publicly write about my experiences, I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to start with &amp;ldquo;all the steps you need to do before you consider yourself doing micro-services the right way&amp;rdquo;.
Some background About a decade back, I was an entry-level software engineer. I was working alone on small projects, while I was breaking into all the new technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, world!</title>
      <link>https://www.koslib.com/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koslib.com/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Yet another attempt to revive my blog and shed some light into stuff I&amp;rsquo;m working on and I personally find interesting. Consider this a personal challenge of myself to express in writing every day stuff that I do and attract my attention, and could potentially be professionally (or not) beneficial for others as well.
In this blog I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing mostly about:
 Python and Go best-practises Microservices and my experiences with service oriented architectures AWS deployments Kubernetes deployments and one thing or two that I pick up on my way  Feel free to DM me on Twitter if you have a topic you&amp;rsquo;d like me to elaborate on, or hop on a brainstorming video chat, or generally just exchange ideas about technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
